好 现在小明有82只苹果
So, Rashad has 82 apples...
和12个朋友
and 12 friends...
大家都饿了
all of whom are hungry.
于是他仔细地看了看苹果
And so he looks carefully at his apples
发现有7只长虫了
and sees that seven have worms.
另外15只烂了
Another 15 have gone rotten.
但是他想力求公平
But he wants to be fair
所以要平均地把好苹果分配出去
and distribute all the good apples equally.
"分配"?
"Distribute"?
就是给出去
Give out.
切 直说不就得了
Well, just say that, yo?
好吧
Okay.
好 那小明的每个朋友分到多少苹果呢
Okay, so how many apples does  each of Rashad's friends get:
A 4; B 5
A, 4; B, 5;
C 6 还是D 7?
C, 6; or D, 7?
慢慢想 快快算
Take your time, but do it fast.
嘿 黑鬼说"我可是有权利(右边)的"
Hey. Nigger said, "l got my rights,"
我兄弟说"哦 是么"
so my boy said,"Oh, yeah?
"给你记左勾拳配你的右边"
Well, he's got a left to go with your right. "
然后就 嘭!
He was like, pow!
- Calvin 你已经算好了么? - 嗯哼
- Calvin, you are done already? - Uh-huh.
- 答案是? - B 5
- Yeah? - B, 5.
你怎么会这么快算好的
How did you work that out so fast?
简单 B 5周围都是点点
Easy."B, 5" got the dinks.
- 都是什么? - 想知道 我说给你听呗
- The what? - If you want, I could show you.
别告诉他 告诉我
Don't show him,show me.
好吧
All right.
你这堂课跟之前的班级上过了吧
You did this with the  earlier math class, right?
所以你就"有82只苹果"...
So, you, like, got 82 apples...
12个黑鬼
12 niggers...
多少多少什么什么
and then how many blah, blah, blah--
然后你就这样
then you went, like,
在这里点点 别的都没有
dinking all round this one and no other one.
所以答案就是B 5
So, answer is "B, 5."
大家都明白了么?
Everybody get that?
耶
Yeah.
B 5周围都是点
"B, 5,"it got all the dinks.
还B 5呢 老子是奥迪五千
"B, 5,"I'm an Audi 5000.
耶
yeah.
火线重案组 第四季 第8集
the.wire.s04e08
* When you walk through the garden *
* you gotta watch your back *
* well I beg your pardon *
* walk the straight and narrow track *
* if you walk with Jesus *
* he's gonna save your soul *
* you gotta keep the devil *
* way down in the hole *
* he's got the fire and the fury *
* at his command *
* well you don't have to worry *
* if you hold on to Jesus hand *
* we'll all be safe from Satan *
* when the thunder rolls *
* just gotta help me keep the devil *
* way down in the hole *
* we'll all be safe from Satan *
* you gotta help me keep the devil *
* way down in the hole *
* keep the devil *
"我们都有自己的角色 可是和大局比起来只是一个棋子 - Zenobia"
首要任务是要确保
The priority should be on making sure
所有过往文件全部更新 所有备注都要输入
the age files are up to date with all notes transcribed,
按照标准公文格式书写
the standard office report.
今天大家执勤的时候
Uh...on our day shift today,
可能会遇到民主党市长候选人 议员Thomas Carcetti
you may encounter Councilman and Democratic  mayoral nominee Thomas Carcetti,
他是来本局调研
who's been fact-finding within the department.
你们要是文件乱放让他看见 小心吃不了兜着走
So, if you go leaving your fax Iying around and he finds them,
最后
Lastly...
可能大家都听说了
as most of you are already aware,
我们的警察局长Raymond Foerster
our ClD Commander Raymond Foerster,
在与癌症长期抗争之后
after a long bout with cancer,
于昨晚在Johns Hopkins医院去世
passed away last night at Johns Hopkins.
溢美之辞难以言表
Better eulogies are coming.
我只想说 他干了整整39年
So, let me just say that  the man served 39 years--
身居副总警监
attaining the rank of colonel--
却从未有过一丝抱怨和背叛
without leaving a trail of bitterness or betrayal.
这在本局不是职业模范 而是奇迹
In this department,that's  not a career, it's a miracle.
今晚是所有警探守灵
There'll be a detective's wake this evening
接下来周三遗体瞻仰 周五落葬弥撒
followed by viewings on Wednesday  and a burial mass on Friday.
家属建议大家向上校最喜爱的慈善机构捐款
The family suggests donations   to the colonel's favorite charities.
地址稍后会贴在咖啡室
The addresses will be posted in the coffee room.
完了
All told.
Bunk 我刚看到你本周的加班记录
And, Bunk, I just got your overtime for the week.
去我办公室把裤子脱了
Get down to my office and pull your pants down.
别别别 搞毛
No no no! Fuck that.
你倒光的 下一壶你煮
You've finished your pot, you make the next one.
好吧
Okay.
我看这儿的都不对
I don't see the right one in here anyway.
- Hauk警司 - 长官
- Sergeant Hauk. - Yes, sir.
我刚和内务部的Beauford见过面
I just got off with Beauford at lAD.
他告诉我有人提交了一起投诉
He tells me there's a harassment complaint been filed.
一个牙买加女人说你拦下她
Some Jamaican woman says you had her stopped
让Amtrak警察搜了她的身
and searched by Amtrak police.
这个我报告里写了
Yeah. Well, you see, in my report,
我们当时认为有确凿证据
we had what we thought was reliable info
证明她在为Marlo Stanfield运毒
that she was a drug courier for Marlo Stanfield.
我们亲眼看到过Stanfield跟她一起
I mean, we actually scoped Stanfield with her.
情报怎么说
What was the info?
这线人很可靠的
The Cl's been reliable.
在我们这一向记录良好
Great track record with us.
合作很久了
Long history.
- 238号线人  - 名字给我
Cl 238.Give me his name.
- 姓名 - 长官
-His name? -Sir.
长官!
Sir!
我觉得这不太好吧
I've never been comfortable with, you know,
在行动组里随便透露线人名字
tossing around names of informants in squad rooms.
我觉得那...
I feel that it's--
- 姓名 - Fuzzy Dunlop 长官
- Name. - Fuzzy Dunlop, sir.
看来我得见见这是何方神圣
I might have to set up a meeting with this character.
他不太愿意见面的
He's kind of leery of meets.
他真的可靠的 我保证
He's been reliable, I promise you.
虽然这次我也搞糊涂了
I mean, this one baffled the shit out of me, too.
不过他从没出过岔子
But he's never been off, never.
你不查清消息就行动 警司
You jumped out on   bad information, Sergeant.
还引入了其他部门
You brought in another agency,
你让本部门丧失了可信度
and you brought discredit to this unit--
我的部门
my unit.
我出发点是好的 长官
In good faith though, sir.
万一有什么后果
Anything comes of this,
你的报告在我手里
I have your report,
看我不用它埋了你
and I will bury you with it.
要是你还没注意到选举结果
And in case you haven't been paying   attention to the election results,
你的拉比已经下台走人了
your rabbi has left the building.
- 今天不发火了? - 有什么意思呢
- No tantrums today? - What's the point?
他们又不会开除我们 不是么
They're not even gonna suspend us, right?
对 有什么意思呢
Right.What's the point?
总之 喜不喜欢我们都在这儿了
So, we're here, like it or not.
如果能让各位好受一点
If it makes you all feel any better,
学校的传言说你们来这儿 是因为你们打败了系统
the word around school is you're down  here because you beat the system.
你们都不想呆在教室里
You had no interest in being in a classroom,
搞得大家都没法上课
and you made the classroom impossible for everybody else,
所以现在你们出来了 你们赢了
and now you are out. You won.
- 哈哈 耶! - 你们觉得自己赢了么
- Ha ha. Yeah! - You feel like winners?
- 一向啊 - 我们一向是人生赢家
- Always. - That's how we did.
"我们"是指谁
Who's we?
- 我们呗 - 不 你们是什么人
- Us. - No, who are you?
- 玩家 - 大佬?
- Players. - Kingpins?
不 大佬要以后才能做
Nah, that comes later.
现在我们只是街角小子
Right now, we are just corner boys.
要多久才能混成大佬
So, how long until you are kingpins?
我想两三年吧
I am thinking two, three years.
两三年
Two, three years.
我问个问题 我要大家都写下来
Let me ask, and I want everybody to write this down--
你们觉得自己十年后会怎样
where do you see yourself in 10 years?
来吧 铅笔白纸
Come on,pencil and paper.
这又不是作业 这是关于你们自己的
This isn't schoolwork, this is about y'all.
她虽年轻 可是很厉害
She's young but she's good.
大学城心理系的博士研究生
Yeah, a doctoral candidate from   the psych department of College Park.
论文写的是社会边缘化及分析
Thesis work is on social alienation and analysis.
好 问到举手
All right, show of hands,
多少写了NBA
how many wrote "NBA"?
对 但是只为湖人队打
Yeah, but only for the Lakers though.
我想当儿童神经外科医生 像那个黑人一样
I want to be a pediatric   neurosurgeon Iike that one nigga,
叫什么名字来着
what's his name?
- Ben Carson - 对 就那家伙
- Ben Carson. - Yeah, that dude.
他是Hopkins医院一位鼎鼎大名的外科医生
He's a black surgeon at Hopkins with a lot of profile.
要想当外科医生 你得上医学院
You want to be a surgeon, you need to go to medical school.
随便啦
Whatever.
多少写了"死掉"?
How many wrote down "dead"?
靠 这都给你猜到
Shit, you saw that coming, huh?
看来可惜了你们只剩那么点时间
It's a shame you   all have so little time,
还要跟我们浪费在这里
and you're wasting it here with us.
你们都知道自己要干什么
You know where you're going.
没什么我们能教而你们不知道的 不是么
We can't teach you anything you don't know about that, right?
咱不是早就说了么
That's what we've been saying.
Namond 把杂志放下
Namond,put away the magazine.
我没在读啥毛杂志
I ain't reading no magazine.
- Namond - 干嘛
- Namond. - What?
这根本不是我的
It ain't even mine.
我进来的时候就在这儿了
It was laying here when I came in.
你们这帮小杂种
Y'all little pissers.
你看 我们把他们教得多好
You know, we are giving them a fine education.
"这不是我的"
"lt ain't even mine.
"我进来的时候就在这里了"
It was just laying here when I came in."
你们全都心里明白--
You know this right here--
这整个破学校
the whole damn school--
他们一举一动
the way they carry themselves,
都是为去街上混做准备
it's training for the street.
学校就像法律 我们就像警察
The building's the system, we the cops.
你们可不是么
Yeah, you are for sure.
你们每天上这儿来
I mean, you'll come in here every day
练习怎么蒙混过关
and practice getting over,
玩各种各样的把戏
try running all different kinds of games.
这不为在街上混做准备么
You know, it's practice for the corner, right?
反正不是真警察 没有真危险
Ain't no real cops. Ain't no real danger.
但是你们多少都学到了些什么
But you'll all getting something out of this.
我看你们自己都没意识到吧
Bet you didn't even know that.
我还宁可在街上混呢
Still I'd rather be out there.
我来吧 街角小子
Can l ? Corner boys, huh?
让我问你们个问题
Let me ask y'all something.
你们越是配合
You know, you help us hone in on this,
我们才能越好地帮助你们
and maybe we do a little   better job with you in here.
- 怎样才能做个出色的街角小子 - 眼睛放亮
- What makes a good corner boy? - Keep your eyes open.
- 账目算清 - 谁都不信
- Keep the count straight. - Don't trust nobody.
帽子底下脑袋不灵光 你就死定了
If you stupid in the hood, you get killed.
就是这样
That's the only way.
我告诉你
And I am telling you,
这个黑笔写的名字有问题 （黑笔表示结案)
this name in black right here got stink on it.
现场目击证人 Bunk
Eyeball witness, Bunk.
Vernon 怎么也跟我回趟现场嘛
Vernon, at least go back to the scene with me
- 重新看一眼 - 你过分了啊 Bunk
- and take a fresh look. - You're out of line here, Bunk.
真的
You are.
好多名字啊 太多了
A lot of names. Too many.
我们能行的
No, we're good with it.
听着 你个躲车后座的杂种
Listen, you back-seat- driving motherfucker,
那家伙就指认了他 Omar他妈的Little
the guy picked him out-- Omar-fucking-Little.
干嘛偏偏挑他 谁他妈在乎啊
Why he picked him out? Who the fuck cares?
我们手上有具女纳税人尸体
We got a dead female taxpayer on our hands,
- 有证人说是他干的 - 我不信
- and somebody's saying him. - I don't buy.
你知道你说的是谁吗
And look who you talking about.
这又不是什么发明了花生62种用途的天才
This ain't the motherfucker that   came up with 62 ways for the peanut.
据我所知五六起案子都有他的名字
His name pops up on five or six cases I know of--
两起还是你的呢 你要我把他放走?
including two of yours-- and you want to put him back on the street?
但这不是他干的
But this ain't him.
这说明有人在耍你们玩
That means someone else is walking on you all.
我告诉你件事 Bunk
Let me tell you something, Bunk:
你下次再抓到人
the next body you catch,
我要一寸寸地检查过来
I'm going to be crawling all over it,
每步都跟你唱反调
second-guessing your ass every step,
调用一切可调用的该死的资源
pulling on every last motherfucking thread.
看你什么滋味
Yeah. We going to see how you like it.
嗨 Vernon
Hey, Vernon.
Vernon Vernon Vernon Vernon
Vernon, Vernon, Vernon, Vernon.
- 跟我一起重新查这案子吧 - 啥?
- Just go back on it with me. - What?
要是查不出什么猫腻
Shit doesn't play out any differently...
我就给你一次让你永生难忘的背部按摩
I'll give you a back rub that you ain't never going to forget.
那个 你们不用因为我在这儿
You know, you guys don't need to do anything
就表现得和平时不一样
you wouldn't normally do just 'cause I'm here.
我还真不知道平时怎么样
I wouldn't know what we normally do around here.
姐新来的没经验
I'm new and inexperienced.
哦 你是...
Oh, you're...
对 我是
Yeah. I am.
真的 我只是想了解一下
Seriously, I'm just trying to get a feel
局里是如何应对暴力的
for the department's response to the violence.
我又不是舍监什么的
I'm not the hall monitor or anything.
你们平时就这样
So, this is your day?
有案子查的时候就不一样了
We catch a body, it's different.
我的摄像机在你这儿吧
I believe you got my camera?
- 我什么? - 驾照 许可证
- I what? - License and registration.
你敬我一尺 我敬你一丈
You do me one, I'll do you.
你有没有名片什么的
You got a card or something?
市里的
City, huh?
摄像机一定得还回来
Video camera gotta come back.
好 我会注意着的
Yeah, well, I see what I can find out about it.
不过摄像机这玩意儿嘛
But you know cameras--
就像暴风雨里的鸽子
kind of like pigeons in the storm.
明白我意思吧
You know what I'm saying?
有时候会飞回来 有时候嘛
Sometimes they come back. Sometimes...
不过我会打听着的
But I keep an ear out on it.
嘿 Jim 他刚说鸽子
Hey, Jim, he just say pigeons?
他耍你呢
He's fucking with you.
你还不如告诉Marimow
Look, you just got to tell Marimow
说你把摄像机装在火车站的电脑上
that you used the camera for the PC at the train station.
然后承认被偷了不就行了
And then just admit the camera got took.
我已经推到线人头上了
I already put it down to the Cl.
我对猪头说了实话
I tell dickhead the truth,
- 他咬着我尾巴不放了 - 哇靠
- he takes my stripes on it. - Oh, come on.
我觉得 你们被停学的时间不长啊
Look, I'm just saying you  weren't suspended that long.
是Till放你们一马
Is it because Tiff dropped it,
还是你们得替Donnelly小姐干什么?
or because you had to do something for Miss Donnelly?
- 干什么啊? - 我也不知道
- Do something? - I don't know,
保证不犯啊什么的
Iike promise or something.
没 Tiff放我们一马 就没事了
No, Tiff dropped it, so it's dropped.
没什么条件的
Ain't nothing past that.
那就好
That's good.
你知道 对付老师和对付警察一个样
You know,the thing with the teachers and cops and whatnot,
他们总是装得好像抓住你尾巴
they always come at you Iike  think they got you by the ass.
可你只要闭紧嘴巴
But you keep your mouth shut,
他们也不能拿你怎么办
ain't nothing they could do.
大多数情况下也就不了了之
So, more times than not, they go away.
说得好
Word on that.
这根本算不了什么 可Anna小姐
I mean, it don't even matter. And Miss Anna...
马上给我订了什么限时放风
she got me on this short leash right now.
除非告诉她去哪儿 否则根本不让我出门
Can't go out the house unless she know right where I'm going.
妈的 能放风就不错了
Shit, at least you've got a leash.
Dewey
Dewey!
你喝的什么鬼东西
What the fuck is that?
俱乐部苏打
Club soda...
加柠檬
and lime.
没种的婊子
Omissive bitch.
还不快去吸个鸡巴算了
Why not just suck a dick and get it over with?
用这个漱漱你那张臭嘴
That will get the bad taste out of your mouth.
跟新的一样
Almost new.
别戴死人的帽子
Don't wear no dead man's hat.
我跟你闹着玩呢
I'm just fuckin' with you.
好 我们来祈祷吧
Here, let's pray.
这里躺着俩纽约小子
Here we lay a couple of New York boys
不知好歹跑到咱南边来
who came too far south for their own fuckin' good.
你妈的北佬现在知道骄傲了吧 臭婊子
Fucking Yankee proud of it now, you fuckin' bitches.
咱们快走吧
Let's get the fuck out of here.
你饿不饿
You hungry?
吃中餐不
You want some Chinese?
不许讲话
No talking.
眼睛看自己的试卷
Keep your eyes on your paper.
Prezbo老师 这写的是汽车啊
Yo, Mr. Prezbo, this say "cars."
怎么了
So?
我们练习时候讲的都是吃的啊
All the stuff we did  in practice was about food.
没关系 只是换个物品而已
It's okay. It's just a different object.
注意数字就好
Pay attention to the number.
数字也乱七八糟
Numbers are messed up, too.
我们没学过1/3
We never did one-thirds.
算法都是一样的1/4 1/5 1/3
It's the same operation-- 1/4, 1/5, 1/3.
步骤相同 只是分母不同而已
Follow the same steps. It's just a different denominator.
1/3辆车怎么算啊
How do you get 1/3 of a car?
应该是所有车的1/3
It's actually 1/3 of all the cars.
哪个跟你讲话了
Was I talking to you?!
如果离的够近
You get close enough...
可以一枪爆头 为什么
you could take a headshot. Why?
因为他有可能穿着防弹衣
'Cause maybe he vested up.
对 打胸可能解决不掉他
Word. A chest shot maybe won't do it for you.
然后呢 你说
Then what? You.
- 轮到他了 - Thug 你就说吧
- It's his turn. - Thug, you on it.
如果要从远处开枪
You gotta shoot from a distance,
就不能冒险打头
you can't risk a headshot.
得打肚子 鸡巴 或者屁股
You go for the belly, the dick or the ass area.
防弹衣保护不到那个地方
Because the vest don't go down that far.
砰 先放倒
Bam! Take them out.
然后呢
Then what?
- 走过去 把他们解决掉 - 打哪儿
- Walk up, finish them off. - With a...?
爆头
Headshot.
妈的 你们不达目的誓不罢休啊
Damn, y'all coming along full effect.
受教 受教
I hear it-- I hear that.
好 万一他在车里面
All right, now say he in a car.
Thomas Hauk警长 巴蒂尔摩警察局
Sergeant Thomas Hauk, Baltimore City Police.
我不是说了市里会来查的么
Didn't I say City would come running?
- 确实 - 我会帮你查查这小丑
- Did. - I'll check this joker out for you.
看他是什么身份
See what's what.
还有件事儿
One other thing,
你事儿办得不错
you're are doing okay running them
把那帮纽约黑鬼赶出东边 我懂
New York niggers of off East Side. I know that.
但是你毁尸灭迹这回事儿嘛...
But this thing you got with disappearing the bodies...
我弟兄说尸体要是就这么消失了
My man is saying if you just vanishing the bodies like that,
这不给咱的效果打折了么
it do kind of defeats its own purpose.
黑鬼还以为他们回Bronx还是怎么的呢
Niggers don't know if they went  back to the Bronx or whatever.
- 你明白? - 当然
- You feel me? - Of course.
我会转告我弟兄的
I'll tell my people.
不是不尊重你的专业精神哈
Hey, no disrespect to your professionalism or nothing.
我们都很钦佩你把那俩混蛋干掉了
We all impressed how you Iose  the motherfuckers like that.
我们只是想传达个信息
We just trying to send a message
让这些纽约佬明白 彻底明白
to these New York people in full effect...
你懂我意思么
you know what I'm saying?
我查完这个告诉你
I'll get back to you on this.
议员
So, Councilman,
听说你昨天在警察局啊
I understand you were a ClD yesterday.
在城里娃那里看到什么新鲜事了
See anything big with those downtown boys?
点的午餐外卖送错了
Well, they messed up the lunch order.
我只想更深入地接触社会
No, I figured I needed  to get closer to the street,
所以今天就上你们这儿来了
so that's why  I am out here today.
跟哥几个看看东区中的东区
Rolling with the mighty is east of the east.
记住 上个礼拜发生了枪击事件
Now, remember, we had a shooting incident last week.
所以要面对着那些街角小鬼 不要被包围了
So, keep those corner fucks to one window. Don't get surrounded.
靠 我记得上次抓了一车
Shit, remember we had a van full of you guys,
- 都跟你这熊样儿似的 - 你他妈说什么呢
- we'd find the fucking chap. - What the fuck you say?
穿成你那样  就连Stevie Wonder（老歌手)都知道你是条子
Dressed like that, Stevie Wonder make you as police.
无线电都藏好 音量调到最响
Keep your radio out of sight. Volume up on those boom boxes.
赌十块钱我们先抓到
10 bucks say we collar up first.
要赌就赌二十
20 makes it worth our while.
市长先生 您知道咱东区兄弟什么最牛么
Mr. Mayor, you know what's great about the Easter?
咱全都像饿狼一样
We are hungry motherfuckers--
当然是褒义
respectfully, I mean.
你刚说
So, you're saying,
不管谁都不能放过?
you don't ever give anybody a break?
- 任何人? - 不能
- Anybody? - Nah nah.
如果你让人短你一块钱
'cause if you let him slide for a dollar,
就等于告诉别人你没种
it's a sign that you're weak.
今天短一块钱 明天就成了两块
Today's dollar is tomorrow's two.
嗯 对自己手下也是这样
Yeah, same with your crew.
你弟兄少了钱来跟你说货丢了有警察什么的
Your boy come up short saying  spillage or police or whatever,
你由着他 他就骑到你头上了
you let him be, and then he gettin' over on you.
- 你就认怂吧 - 所以要好好弄死他
- Then you a chump. - So, you got to fuck him up.
- 对 - 额 你要 好好教训他
- Yeah. - You gotta, ahem, mess him up.
不 真出了大事 才惩罚他
Nah nah. Something for real happen, you do that.
如果为一点小事就发飙
If you do it over some bullshit,
你只会失去员工的信任
then all you did was lose a good worker.
不 不
Oh, no.
你要好好教训那黑鬼
Man, you gotta fuck that nigger up, man.
喂喂喂
Whoa whoa whoa whoa!
喂
Whoa!
别都一窝蜂一起说
Stop talking on top of each other.
你们在街头上也这样说话么
This how you communicate out on them streets?
好吧 我看这么着 你兄弟回来
All right, it's like this: you boy come back to you,
- 跟你说怎么怎么了 - 你就弄死他
- say this happened, that happened-- - Then you fuck him up.
我觉得 该让他从自己的提成里赔
In my mind, I'm gonna let him make it out of his own cut, too.
如果他是个好员工  他也知道该怎么做
If he good worker, he know what he need to do.
对 说得有道理
Yeah, he got a point.
他说得对 这办法不错
He got a point. That's a good one.
如果他想了想
If he thinks about it,
还说不是他的错
says it ain't his fault,
那就是他玩你了
then that nigger run a game on you.
然后你再弄死他
And then you fuck that nigger up.
- 对 - 就是 对
- Yeah. - All right, yeah.
- 为什么呢 - 必须这么办啊
- But why? - You know it gotta happen, man.
你懂我意思吧
You know what I'm saying!
等等 一个个说
Wait wait wait! One voice. One voice.
- 喂 一个个说 - 喂喂 D 你告诉他
- Y'all, one voice. - Yo, yo, D, you tell him.
总是有人看着的
There always people watching.
看着你
Watching... you.
对 对
True. Yeah.
你们怎么这么久才来
What's taking you boys so long?
他来了
There he is now.
快快 就是他
Hurry up, hurry up, this guy.
就是这家伙
This guy right here.
去你妈的 喂喂喂
Fuck you, guys. Hey, yo, yo.
喂 兄弟 我们要买药片
Yo, man,we need some pills.
算你找对地方了
Yeah, you in the right place, man.
去帮我们买
Get them for us.
拜托 我赶着去上班
Come on, man, I'm going to work.
喂 20块买药片 10块给你
Yo, 20 for the pills and 10 for you.
- 自行车留下 - 干嘛 想偷我车?
- Leave the bike. - What, you want steal my bike?
我他妈要你车干嘛
What the fuck I want your bike for?
老子自己有车
I got a car.
等我一会儿
Give me a minute.
20块对你也许不算什么
$20 might not mean nothing to you.
我可不像你挣那么多
But I ain't making that much money.
咱都是血汗钱
It's hard money.
你们这帮懒鬼
Y'all some lazy motherfuckers.
明明就在街角
This shit is right around the corner.
哥几个别提有多感谢你了
You have no idea how much we appreciate this.
我就喜欢看他们这样去上工
I love it when they come to work pumped like this.
我靠
Shit.
拜托 我是去上班啊
Come on, man. I'm going to work.
别介啊 兄弟 我真是去上班的
Come on, man. I'm going to work, man!
搞毛啊 伙计
It's bullshit, man!
都他妈搞什么飞机
This is some bullshit right here.
真的 真的 我可没药 我身上啥都没有
For real! For real! I ain't got no drugs, no shit on me.
我身上啥都没有 你们连我车都要拿?!
I ain't got nothing on me, man. And you taking my bike, too?!
车不能拿 你们这是陷害我
I need that.This is  bullshit y'all be using!
- 抓了一个 - 装神弄鬼地唬我们
- One down. -...comin' in the hood fuckin' with us.
你们太他妈混蛋了
This is fucked up right here, man.
Andre 你怎么样
Andre, how you doing?
这是我朋友 Moreland警探
This is a friend of mine-- Detective Moreland.
你最近怎么样啊
You doing okay there or what?
听着 既然我朋友在这儿
So, listen, for my friend here,
你不如再说一遍当时的事情经过吧
tell me one more time how  the thing went down, will you?
- 那男孩冲进来 - Omar?
- The boy came in. - Omar?
- Omar - 他用9mm指着她
- Omar. - He puts the nine on her.
对我说"都交出来"
Says to me, "Whatever you got."
9毫米口径的么?
A nine, huh?
你当时站哪儿
Where were you?
- 就在现在这个位置 - 嗯
- Where you see me at. - Mm-hmm.
9mm可打不穿这个
Nine wouldn't go through this.
- 你干嘛出来? - 他让我出来的
- Why did you come out? - 'Cause he said to.
想英雄救美呢
Trying to save her life.
对 我说过了
Right, I'm saying---
这玻璃跟英格兰银行似的
This is like Bank of England glass.
跟Knox碉堡似的
Fort Knox glass.
这又是谁搞出来的
And who put that up there? Huh?
那家伙得有把猎大象的枪才能打穿吧
Guy must have had an elephant gun or some shit.
我怎么知道 那小子呆着面罩
I don't know. The boy had a mask on.
面罩哈
A mask, eh?
像佐罗是吧
Like Zorro, huh?
- 这是什么时候的事儿 - 几个星期以前吧
- When did that happen? - A few weeks back.
- 报警了没 - 我给忘了
- Put in a report? - It got away from me.
Andre
Andre.
我们需要你到警局来一趟
We're going to need you to come down to the office
有几件事情 你得说说清楚
and straighten out a couple of things.
我还要做生意呢
I'm running a business here.
俺哪儿都不去
I ain't going nowhere.
给我来瓶Mylanta
Give me a bottle of Mylanta.
谢谢
Please.
他满口胡扯 你知道为什么吗
His whole story is fucked, and here's why,
首先 这不合理啊
First, it don't make any sense.
枪手打死了那女人
The shooter took out the woman
留他一活口在这儿跟你讲话
and left him breathing to talk to you.
要死他也死了
He should be dead, too.
其次 这后面是个藏毒点
Second, there's a drug depot in there.
防弹玻璃 加固钢窗
The glass, reinforced steel,
监控 没多少存货
camera, low inventory.
三 那.50枪孔他在给我们打马虎眼
And, third,he's shining us on  about that big-ass.50-cal hole
我知道是谁干的
because I know who put it there,
他也知道是谁干的
and he knows who put it there.
如果他说
And if he were to say,
"哦那个 那是Omar上次干的
"Oh, that? That's Omar's previous.
连着袭击了两次这地方 --"
Ripping off a re-up in here--"
其实就是那样-- 那他就完了
which is what happened-- he be fucked.
怎么着
So what?
一个家伙第一次拿着把.50步枪进来
A guy comes in the first time with a.50 caliber
知道玻璃很厚
because he knows  the glass is thick,
回去过一星期换了把9毫米的?
then comes back the next week with a nine?
干咱这行可不能挑自己喜欢的故事啊
The job isn't about picking the stories we like best.
狗娘养的 你还教训起我怎么干活来了
Motherfucker. Now you're going to lecture me about what the job is.
- 我错了 - 好吧 回城吧
- My apologies. - Okay. Let's go downtown.
现在有新法律了
It's a new law, yo--
三粒药 就是重罪了
three pills, that's felony weight.
你还是登记在册的街角小子?
And you're on a pre-indicted corner?
- 啥? - 你最好把存货交出来
- What? - You better show some stash.
现在牢里可没人管了
Oh, it's off the chart now.
那些特区小子们
Those DC boys down  there,too, right.
就喜欢巴尔的摩嫩菊花
They love fresh Baltimore ass.
- 哼哼 - 我啥存货都没有啊
- Mm-mmm. - I ain't know no stash.
他们说干菊花比干妞还爽呢
They say it's better than pussy.
- 这是我的药 - 好哇
- Those my pills. - Yeah.
你没听说过联邦指导法么
Have you ever heard of federal guidelines?
登记在册的街角小子
Pre-indicted corners,homeboy.
至少关三年 除非你缓刑
That's three years mandatory. Unless you mitigate.
- 缓...什么? - 交出货来 臭小子
- Mit-a-what? - The stash, front boy.
我不知道啥存货 这是我的药 大哥
I don't know no stash. Those my pills, man.
我现在就嗨着呢 你看
I'm high right now, look.
行啊
Yeah.
他们一定爱死他了 走吧
They gonna love him up in there. Come on.
- 我先看见他的 - 是么
- I saw him first. - Yeah?
- 小杂种是我的 - 真的是我的药 我发誓
- Bitch is mine. - Those are my pills, I swear.
俩了
That's two.
给我进车里去吧
Get the fuck in the car.
妈的 分数哈
Damn, fractions?
他教我们分数
He's doing fractions.
你知道我们新的课上干了什么
Shit, you want to know what we  talked about in my new class today?
- 什么 - 玩弹弓
- What? - Slinging.
老子才不玩呢
Yo, I'm not playing.
我们说的是怎么做买卖
We talked about business,
怎么去社会上混
about putting shit on the damn street.
黑鬼 算了吧
Nigga, please.
简直像我们在教他们
It was like we schooling them.
我的新班级简直烂透了
Yo, my new class is the shit.
- 你今天去不去健身房 - 不去
-Yo, you going by the gym today? -No, man.
我得赶紧把剩下的货装瓶 好去进货
I gotta go vial up what's left  on this package so I can re-up.
好吧
All right.
- 好吧 - 回见
- All right, man. - Peace, man.
那倒是简单
That shit is easy though, right?
我快要走了 Duquan
I got to leave soon,Duquan.
好
Okay.
你玩到几级了?
What level are you on?
啊 我从没超过十级过
Ah, I never made it past 10.
想看我玩到40级么
Want to see me get to 40?
这是作弊
That's cheating.
想要我教你么
Want me to show you how?
巴尔的摩市警察局
Baltimore City Police Department.
对 女士 我叫Sydney Handjerker(手淫者)
Yes, ma'am, this is Sydney Handjerker
是Handjerker Cohen & Bromburg律师行的
with Handjerker, Cohen & Bromburg.
我想找一位Thomas Hauk警长
I'm trying to locate a Sergeant Thomas Hauk
我是代表一位客户想见他
in regards to a client I am representing.
请稍等
Hold, please.
市长办公室 Hoskins警监
Mayor's office, Lieutenant Hoskins.
啊 你好
Yes, hello.
我是Pepper, Pepper & Bayleaf律师行的
This is Ervin Pepper of  Pepper,
Ervin Pepper (胡椒 胡椒 & 香草)
Pepper& Bayleaf.
我找一位Thomas Hauk警司有点事
I'm calling in regards to a Sergeant Thomas Hauk in regards to a--
他已经不在这里干了 请稍等
He's no longer on this detail. Hold on for a minute.
重案组 有什么事吗
Major Crimes. May I help you?
我是Jay医生 Thomas Hauk的报告出来了
This is Dr. Jay calling with test results for Thomas Hauk.
他在出外勤
He's on the street.
您要留言吗?
You want to leave a message?
喂
Hello:
动手吧
Let's do it.
你朝他直走过去 明白?
You've just got to walk up on him, all right?
速战速决
Snap one.
你先要确认好他从纽约来的
We've gotta make sure he's from New York first, right?
要问他
Gotta ask.
问什么 "你是纽约来的么"
Ask what? "You from New York?"
不 问个巴尔的摩的问题
No, ask a Baltimore question,
问个纽约黑鬼不知道的
something a New York nigger won't know.
- 巴尔的摩问题是怎样的 - 不知道
- What's a Baltimore question, yo? - I don't know,
像本地酒吧音乐什么的
Iike, maybe something about club music.
他们在纽约的都不懂这个的
They don't know nothing about that shit up in New York.
哈
Huh:
问他 Young Leek是谁
Ask him, like, who Young Leek be.
* 摇一摇 乐一乐*
Shaking and jiggle it.
或者K-Swift (都是乐队名)
Or K-Swift.
那些92Q的东西我一点都不知道哇
Man, I know nothing about that 92Q shit, man.
老兄 谁管这些呀
Man, who gives a fuck, yo?
你不知道Marc Clarke?
You don't know Marc Clarke?
"大肥仔晨间秀"?
"The Big Phat Morning Show"?
你有毛病啊 丫头
You ain't right, girl.
正常巴尔的摩黑鬼都知道这些好吗
The average Baltimore nigga is gonna know all that shit, all right?
他们纽约人听的都是些垃圾
They listen to some bullshit up in New York.
这都他妈乱扯啥
This is some bullshit.
- 去吧 - 好吧 随便了
- Go ahead. - All right, whatever.
我刚跟兄弟打赌
Hey, got a bet going on, man.
- 怎么了 - "大肥仔晨间秀"里
- What's up? - Who's your favorite one
你最喜欢哪个?
on "The Big Phat Morning Show," yo?
干嘛 你纽约来的么 当然是Sonjay
What, are you a New York, girl?Sonjay.
- 谁 谁 - 他一出场就绝了
- Who? Who? - Kill that show any day.
Snoop Snoop 喂 喂
Snoop! Snoop, yo! Snoop, yo! Yo!
住手 Sonjay也是那个秀里的
Chill! Sonjay be on the show too.
下次还是换我问问题吧
So maybe I ask the questions from now on, all right?
他们打赌玩儿着钓上了个倒霉蛋
And then they basically entrap some poor bastard on a bet,
为了二十块的毒品就把人关起来
haul in $20 worth of drugs.
然后审他 栽赃他
Now they've got to process him, feed him,
扣押了他的自行车
property voucher his bike.
接着 还抓了个14岁的烟鬼
Next thing,they're working on some 14-year-old  smoke
把人当本拉登似的拷问
hound like he's Bin Laden.
所谓大买卖不过是三小瓶可卡因
The big haul there is three vials of cocaine.
你就睁只眼闭只眼么
I mean,are you with this?
这个问题由来已久
I've been fighting this bullshit for years.
唯一的解决办法是高层插手
The only way to go is high-end enforcement.
你挑个在外面惹事儿的家伙
You pick the targets that'll make a dent out there,
减少暴力执法
reduce the violence.
有什么问题么
So what's the problem?
问题是 我也是照章办事
Problem is I do what I'm told.
怎讲
Meaning?
市长先生 我不是比你更种族歧视
Mr. Mayor, I'm no more a racist than you are.
关于抓捕行动
The thing about affirmative action--
我就事论事 无意冒犯
I'm just talking policy here, no offense intended--
- 但说无妨 - 这是个数字游戏
- None taken. - --it's a numbers game.
数字游戏产生更多的数字游戏
And numbers games breed more numbers games.
你要多雇佣20%黑人警官
You need a 20% hike in the hiring of black officers
来提升城市人口形象
to keep up with the city demographic.
但这又必须在另一边反应出来
But that's also got to be reflected straight up the chain,
有些抓人上就不免急功近利--
which means fast-tracking some people past where their--
怎么说呢
how do I say this--
已经形成潜规则了
there are experienced warrants.
一边数字上升更好看了
And he who owes his good fortune to the numbers,
另一边也要跟着上
abides in them.
逮捕率也要提高15-20%
Gotta show arrests are up 15, 20%.
质量只能以后再说了
We'll worry about the quality later.
你在外头看到的 就是猫鼠游戏
So what you saw out there, it's a con game,
治标不治本
a Band-Aid on cancers.
我不是睁只眼闭只眼 只是照章办事
So no, I'm not with this, but I do follow orders.
当然 如果上头的规则有变
However, if those orders were to change,
或者我有机会自己改变规则...
or if I had the opportunity to change them myself...
喔不 你不是吧
Oh no, you not!
这东西怎么会在我家
What's this shit doing in my house?
我装瓶子呢 妈
I stretching bottles, Ma.
你见过你爸把活带回来的么
You ever see your daddy bring his  work home with him like that?
不然要个警督干嘛
That's what you got a lieutenant for.
要是警察而不是你妈这么走进来
Police come through this door instead of your mother,
这房子就都没了
they will have this whole damn house.
从今往后给我上别处装去
This has all got to be packed up and elsewhere right now.
好啦 急什么
All right, be cool.
让Bey知道看你怎么办
Wait till Bey hears about this.
你听见没那家伙全都推到种族问题上
Did you hear that naked-ass appeal to racial solidarity?
我真想踢死他的白人屁股
I'd like to kick his pale entitled ass.
你听他说了什么
Were you listening?
"我不是比你更种族歧视"
He's no more a racist than I am.
看来你也挨踢了
Might have to kick your ass, too.
你听说过那个叫Daniels的么?
What have you heard about this fellow Daniels?
"西区警长"
Major in the Western.
对 他不错
Yeah, he's there,
不过没什么政治势力
but not much politically.
他好像哪边都不站
I don't think he's got any suction with anybody.
杂烩饭呢?
Where's the Rice-A-Roni?
妈 杂烩饭呢?
Ma, where's the Rice-A-Roni?
我在车站看到个男孩
There was this boy on the stoop
看上去快饿死了
that looked like he was starving.
你热给他吃了?
So you cooked it for him?
没 我就这么给他了
Naw, I just gave it to him.
你就这么给他了
You just gave it to him.
一整盒生的他就这么吃了?
Boy ate a raw box of Rice-A-Roni?
说 你把我们家杂货卖了多少钱
How much did you sell the groceries for?
别这么看着我
Don't look at me like that.
我要出去了
I gotta go out.
- 才十块? - 你不是有卖杂烩饭的钱么
- $10? - You have your Rice-A-Roni profits.
Michael 搞毛啊
Michael, come on!
小子 我让你拿着社保卡
Boy, I ain't gonna let you hold the DSS card
可不是让你这样对我的
if you ain't gonna do right by me.
你必须让我拿着那卡
You're gonna let me hold that card.
你个倔娃子
You're a hard child.
下次别卖我们的口粮了!
Next time, don't go selling the food out of our mouths!
就像你们说的
Yeah, like y'all say--
不要撒谎骗人
don't lie, don't bunk,
不要偷拐抢骗 什么什么的
don't cheat, don't steal, or whatever.
可你们呢
But what about y'all, huh?
怎么 算是政府的了?
What, the government?
什么海洛因 哈
What it-- Enron? Ha!
类固醇
Steroids, yeah.
酒水买卖
Liquor business:
卖酒才叫谋财害命呢
Booze is the real killer out there.
还有香烟 我操
And cigarettes-- oh, shit.
你口袋里有烟没有?
Hey, you got some smokes in there?
我正努力戒烟
I'm trying to quit.
你工资不也是靠毒品来的
And drugs paid your salary, right?
不能这么说 不过我明白你意思
No, not exactly, but I get your point.
我们干的和你们一样一样的
We do the same thing as y'all,
只不过换成我们干
except when we do it,
人们就说"天哪 这帮小畜生"
it's like,"Oh my God,  these kids is animals."
弄得跟世界末日似的
Like it's the end of the world coming.
靠 这太扯了好嘛
Man, that's bullshit, all right?
这就叫 那啥 道 -- 道貌岸然
'Cause it's like-- what is it-- hypocrite-- hypocritical.
我们都有自己的角色
I mean, yeah, we got our thing,
但和大局比起来只是一个棋子
but this is just part of the big thing.
就是
Exactly.
可这个街角小子的活儿
But this corner-boy thing, right?
你们只是嘴上说说而已
All y'all did all this talking up in here.
难道能坐下来
You think you could sit down
把行为准则一条条写下来?
and write down the laws to your thing?
废话 我这就写给你看
Hell yeah. I'll do it right now.
切
Shit.
不 我是说你们能不能一起写?
No, I'm talking about-- can y'all do it together?
我考一次分数运算
I give the test on fractions,
一半孩子都崩溃了
half the kids have breakdowns.
还有很多孩子连整数都算不清楚
I still have a lot of kids who can barely handle whole numbers.
你不是一个人
Well, if it's any comfort,
我教的高年级班
I have outside of my advanced class
有半打阅读还不如小学生水平
maybe half a dozen reading at grade level.
我还指望教他们背元素周期表呢
Try having them on the periodic table of elements.
不管怎样 这是你的大纲
The thing is, it's your curriculum,
你得按着大纲教
and you have to stick to it.
- 没法教 教不会啊 - 你没得选
- I can't. It's absurd. - You have to.
政府接管不接管这所学校
That test in April is the difference
就看四月份的这场考试了
between the state taking  over the school or not.
还不如让政府接管呢
Maybe the state should.
呐 教数学 无非是应付考试
Look, you teach math, you teach the test.
North Avenue就是唱唱
North Avenue is all about
"一个都不能拉下"的高调
the leave-no-child-behind stuff getting spoon-fed.
那他们能学些什么呢
And what do they learn?
想办法折中处理
Find some middle ground.
每天教点国家规定的内容
Every day try to do a little for the statewide,
把单元概要写在黑板上 给Donnelly看
and keep a unit problem on the blackboard for Donnelly.
万一她来视察的话
You know,if she comes to visit,
她会觉得你都讲在点子上
she thinks you're on point.
剩下的时间么
The rest of the time,
你爱干嘛干嘛
do what you feel like you need to do.
不过要小心点
But be careful.
你离评估通过还远着呢
You're are still on the far side of your evaluation.
第一年不关孩子们什么事儿
The first year isn't about the kids,
你自己得先熬过来
it's about you surviving.
站起来
get up!
手放脑后
Hands on your head.
- 我还没吃完呢 - 吃你妈
- I was eating that. - Fuck you.
- 那是我的午饭 - 饭你妈
- That's my lunch. - Fuck you.
靠墙跪下 小兔崽子
Find a wall, motherfuckers. Man.
脚靠后
Get your feet up.
- 你这是骚扰 - 我说什么了我
- This is harassment. - What did I say to you?
"X你妈"你刚对我说的
"Fuck you." That's what you said to me.
这儿什么都没有 老兄
There's nothing here,man.
哟 不好意思
Oops. My bad.
你跟我玩是吧
You want to play games with me?
老子敢让你们每天都吃不了兜着走
I'm going to be in your people's shit like this every day
除非把摄像机给我还回来
until my camera comes home.
听到没 每一天
You hear me? Every day.
你 你们几个 咱们走
You and yours. Let's go.
啊 感觉真好
Ah, that felt good!
老西区扫毒组东山再起
The old Western DEU rides again.
请进
Yes?
所有警察局成员到总台报到
Anyone from the ClD reports at the front desk.
Any ClD reports to the front desk.
恕我直言 先生  您最好走正规渠道通过指挥部
Respectfully, sir, I would  feel better if you cleared this
来下达命令
through the chain of command.
是 长官
Yes, sir.
我会考虑的
I'll think about that.
- 老板们找麻烦? - 其中一个
- Problem with the bosses? - One in particular.
- 就是未来市长 - Carcetti?
- That was our mayor-to-be. - Carcetti?
真的?
Seriously?
他想见面
He wants to meet.
你和他 单独见面?
You and him? Alone?
他想谈谈警察局的事
He wants to talk about the police department--
什么可行 什么不可行
what works,what doesn't.
连市长都要听你的意见啦
You have the mayor's ear now.
你看你
Look at you.
问题是 我说什么呢?
Here's the thing: What do I say?
什么叫你说什么
What do you mean what do you say?
我该说多少实话呢
How honest should I be:
光谈技术问题和执法战略
I mean, it's one thing for me to talk technical shit
是一回事情
or enforcement strategies,
但那些实实在在发生的事情呢
but the shit that actually goes on?
我要是一开口 都不知道停不停得下来
I start talking about that, I don't know if I can stop.
Cedric 这是你的机遇
Cedric, this is your chance.
你就要平步青云了
This is a career.
万一我把枪口对准Burrell和Rawls
What if I take my shots at Burrell and Rawls
可他不打算清理门户 我怎么办
and he decides not to clean house? What then?
新市长打电话给你
The new mayor calls you up,
想让你采取行动
asks you for your take on things,
怎么 你倒不想蹚政治浑水?
and you don't want to be, what, a politic?
Carcetti 我都不了解这个人
Carcetti-- ugh. I don't even know the man.
既然他打给你
If he is calling you,
就说明Burrell和Rawls那伙人 已经撞在枪口上了
it's because guys like Burrell and Rawls are on the ropes.
- 也许吧 - 我知道这有风险
- Maybe. - I know there is a risk,
可说不定这次就能...
but maybe I'd fire away...
一箭双雕
both barrels.
我就在这儿等着 放风
I'll wait out here, man.Up top.
我等 我等
I'll wait, I'll wait.
左手拿勺 右手拿瓢
You got that grub, you got that pot?
我等
Aw, wait.
-"摇一摇来晃一晃" - 干嘛
-Shaking and jiggle it. -Yo.
谁唱的?
Who made that track?
你特么跟谁说话呢 小子?
Yo, who you talking to,dawg?
老子问你Young Leek是谁
I'm asking who Young Leek be.
你是说二肥他表弟?
You mean 2 Phat's cousin?
- 谁? - 错
- Who? - No.
黑鬼 我他妈怎么会知道
Nigga, then how the fuck should I know?!
你他妈知道自己跟谁--
Yo, who the fuck is you talking--
- 哇靠 - 不赖哇
- Aw, shit. - Not bad.
干那黑鬼
Fuck that nigga.
干嘛呢 B?
What up, B?
- 妈呢? - 楼上
- Where Ma at? - Upstairs.
Michael 我爸回来了
Michael, my daddy came home.
爸回来了?
Daddy came home?
- 看谁回来了 - Michael
- Look who home! - Michael.
靠 长高了哇
Damn, you grew.
给Macia拿包Kools烟
And a pack of Kools for Macia.
还对那小丑死心塌地啊?
Still tricking for that clown?
我就不懂你们干嘛都说他坏话
You know, I don't understand why people talk trash about him.
我知道他是爱我的
All I know is he loves me.
等你跟厌了他
Well, when you get tired of him
脑子清醒过来了
going upside your head and all,
你才能明白谁最爱你呢
you'll really know who loves you.
随便啦
Whatever.
哇
Whoa.
你老母 怎么啦?
Motherfucker, what?
他判了12年啊
He had 12 years.
假释了
Parole.
只是卖药而已
It was only a drug charge.
你发誓说他不会回来的
You swore he wasn't coming back.
这是件好事啊 Michael
This is a good thing,Michael.
一切都回到从前的样子了
It's going to be back the way it was.
从前的样子
The way it was?
我们又是一家人了
We a family again.
你骗我
You lied to me.
人是会变的 Michael
People change, Michael.
他还说让你把独立卡还给他
He said you can give him back the independence card too.
他会照顾我们大家的
He gonna take care of all that for us.
感谢您从华府远道而来
Thanks for coming up from Washington.
党内很珍视这次机会
The party is happy for the opportunity.
你这次算是抓到重点了
You've got some heat behind you at this point.
- 言归正传 - 按我们的意思
- But down to business. - The way we see it,
我们要搞次全市范围的大清洗
we've got to cobble together a citywide turnaround,
起名叫"巴尔的摩奇迹"或什么的
call it the "Baltimore Miracle" or some shit.
以犯罪率下降10%为始
Which starts with a 10% drop in crime.
这本来就是你的竞选口号
Since that was your campaign cry,
- 你要争取两位数 - 毫无疑问
- you want the double digits. - No doubt.
Denny要在市区竖一座钢筋水泥建筑
Denny's got to do a bricks-and-mortar project downtown,
以他的名字命名
put his name on something.
体育馆已经多得濮出来了
We're flushed with stadiums,
酒店不考虑在内
got hotels out of the ass.
你们有好的戒毒中心么?
You guys got a good convention center?
- 还有个在扩建中 - 总之要造点什么
- And a convention center expansion. - Gotta put something up,
竖个标志 上面写:
get the sign on it that says,
"由Tommy Carcetti与巴尔的摩市民 共同向您呈现"
"Brought to you by Tommy Carcetti and the citizens of Baltimore."
那就先想想 不过要抓紧时间决定
Well, think on it,but you don't  have too much time to decide.
还有其他事么?
Anything else?
教育在民调中一向反映良好
Education always polls good.
不行 学校碰不得
Oh no, we've got to stay away from schools.
前四任政府留给我们
Our last four  administrations Ieft us
一堆内部系统的内部烂摊子
with an inner-city system with inner-city problems.
我们一掺和进去指手画脚
We get involved, start talking shit,
就成了我们的问题了
it becomes our mess.
小心水深着呢
Gotta respect the depths.
一 你让犯罪率降下来
One, you get the drop in crime;
二 你在市中心建栋楼
two, you build something downtown;
三 别管学校的事儿
and three, you stay away from schools;
四 继续保持你那正太脸
And, four, you keep your boyish good looks.
做到这些 到2008你说不定就能竞选州长了
You do all that, you might be  running for governor in 2008,
也许能把州府给我们赢回来 嗯?
maybe take back that statehouse for us, hmm?
- 能把角弄成方的不? - 简单
- Can you get him a square corner? - Easy.
你没事吧
You okay?
没事
Yeah.
你确定?
You sure?
- 是家里的事儿么? - 不是
- Is it something at home? - No.
- 说吧 - 都说没事儿了
- Come on. - I said no.
好吧
Okay.
如果有什么你想说的...
If there's ever anything you want to talk about...
尽管跟我说 或者如果你愿意
there's me,but if you'd rather,
我可以给你写张条子让你跟社工谈
I can write you a pass to see the social worker.
随便什么时候
Just say when.
Michael 你想跟社工谈谈么?
Michael, do you want to see the social worker?
不想
No.
不得不说
I have to say,
我从没见过在课堂上这么活跃的孩子
I've never seen kids like them  this animated in a classroom.
这么专注 至少在边缘儿童中没见过
Focused-- the corner culture kids, at least.
有深层问题的孩子 一般不会这样
The ones with deeper problems, they opted out of that.
深层问题?
Deeper problems:
我们不是在这谈边缘法则
We're not just up against corner logic in there.
我看到有对立性反抗异常
I am seeing oppositional defiant disorders,
临床抑郁 应激性压力症状
clinical depression, post traumatic stress,
那个叫Shaundra的女孩  可能有边界性精神病
and with the girl Shaundra, borderline psychoses maybe.
要真有这些问题
With those type of problems,
我们看来得请个全职社工了
we are gonna have to have a social worker here full-time.
但这些街角孩子 他们真的很活泼
But the corner kids, yeah, they really came alive.
当他们谈到自己熟悉的东西
Yeah, when they talk about what they know,
目标明确 表达清晰
they talk from here, and they stay on point.
天 他们还知道轮着说
Shit, they have been even taking turns in there.
问题是
Question is:
对他们不了解的东西 我们能激起相同热情吗
Can we get them in that kind  of mindset on stuff they don't know?
能让他们为学习而学习吗?
Can we have them learn on faith alone?
说实话 这可是未知的领域啊
In all honesty, this is uncharted territory.
我们该从何做起呢
Where do you go from here?
不如先上马
How about we just let this ride,
走一步看一步?
see where it takes us?
好 事情就是这样
All right, see, here's the thing:
一旦接了 这活就是你的
Once you got it, it's all you.
出了什么碴子 我就要给你颜色看
Anything happen, I'm gonna have to fuck you up.
这还不算什么
Yeah, but that's nothing.
把活交给我的人 Marlo
'Cause the guy trusting me on this-- Marlo--
他会杀了你 还有你全家
he'll kill you and your whole family.
所以别偷鸡摸狗的
So don't go shaking the bottles
Marlo每次都会称分量
'cause Marlo weighs that shit every time.
- 我什么都不会偷的 - 谅你也不敢
- I ain't shaking shit. - See that you don't,
你要是干了 我一定会知道
'cause if you do fuck with it, I'm gonna know.
好 这就行了
All right, that's good.
好 这样很好
All right, it's good.
好了 你看 你未满13岁
All right, see, you're under 13 and shit.
除了我和Marlo 谁都动不了你
So you're safe from everybody but me and Marlo.
- 那我现在算是队长了? - 对
- So I'm a lieutenant now? - Yeah.
你是我的队长
You're my lieutenant.
可我才多挣十美元?
And all I get is an extra $10?
嗯 把手上的活干好了我们再谈
Yeah, you do this good, and we'll talk.
看见这位老兄么?
See this guy here?
这是最高法庭检察官
That's the grand jury prosecutor.
你对我们撒谎 不过是玩笑
Now, you lie to us, it's just good clean fun.
要是对这位西装革履的老兄说谎 靠!
But you tell tales to that three-piece motherfucker, ooh, shit!
我没有撒谎
I ain't telling lies.
Gary 我假设性地问你
Hey, Gary, let me ask you this hypothetically:
证人对你们法庭说谎最多能判多少
How much time does a witness get for lying to your grand jury?
开玩笑吧 能判多久判多久
Are you kidding? As much as I can get him.
- 最多几年? - 十年
- What's the max? - 10 years.
哦 居然能判十年啊?
Oh, you've got people going away for 10 years?
是啊 常有的事儿
Oh, hell yeah, all the time.
十年呐
10 years!
我还以为他会说两三年呢
I thought he was going to say, like, two or three.
那家伙把我暴打一顿
Hey, look, that motherfucker went upside my head.
我眼冒金星看不清啊
I couldn't even see straight.
你说的杂种到底是谁呢?
Which motherfucker are we talking about?
后来他们又让我吃了那药
Then they got me on that medication.
让我晕晕乎乎的
It made me groggy as shit.
这家伙就开始对我拳打脚踢的--
Then this man starts working at me--
- 踢你妈! - 哇靠
- Fuck I did! - I mean, shit!
我现在还晕着呢 我得去--
I'm still groggy now. I mean, I got to--
这里有没有洗手间啊
is there a washroom around:
- 说谎的杂种 - 可不是么
- Lying motherfucker. - For real.
靠边停 杂种
Pull over, asshole.
靠
Shit.
从车里出来
Step out of the car,please.
Step out of the car.
手放车上
Put your hands on the car.
身上有东西么?
Got anything on you?
- 坐路边上 - 坐下
-Have a seat on the curb. -Have a seat.
双脚交叉 手放在脑后
Cross your feet. Put your hands on your head.
这什么玩意儿?
What the fuck is this powder?
我妈园子里种的柠檬
Lime from my mama's garden.
你用这造什么 俱乐部么?
What are you building,a clubhouse?
这可是汽钉枪 小心点
Oh, that shoot nails. Be cool.
我当然知道这是啥
Oh, I know what it does.
把摄像机给我还回来
I want my fucking camera.
我听到你那天在Comstat说的话了
I heard what you said at Comstat the other day.
我也听说你是个深谙警务的指挥官
I also hear you're a commander who knows police work.
大家说说而已
That's what people are saying.
昨天我在东区跟着出了一次警
So, yesterday I did a ride-along in Eastern,
看他们在街上缉毒 便衣抓人
watched street pops, undercover rips.
你觉得我怎么想?
So what am I thinking?
我猜 您看到的是时间财力物力的浪费
My guess:You witnessed a waste of time, money, energy,
以及在某些案子中 人力
and, in few cases, talent.
Rawls说这要怪Burrell和他的数字游戏
Rawls says it's Burrell and his numbers game.
他说如果我拿他开刀 把他推到枪口上
He says if I unleash him, put him in the driver's seat,
那不过是东边不闹南边闹
then all that bullshit goes south.
重大犯罪案件会大幅增加
See a return of high-end police work,
会比黎明前还要黑暗
says it'll be the dawning of a new day.
- 这话Rawls说的? - 对
- Rawls said that? - Yeah.
说他也只是照章办事
Says he's just following orders,
做个好战士
being a good soldier.
你怎么看
What do you say?
市长先生 你要是想跟我谈街上的事儿
Mr. Mayor, if you want to talk to me about what happens in the street
或者我管辖下西边的情况
or what goes on under me in the Western,
包管你听得耳朵起茧子
I'll talk your ear off.
但我也是个战士
But I'm a soldier too.
我不能越权发表自己的意见
I don't go up the chain with my opinions.
这我能够尊重
I can respect that.
不过我要说一句
I will say this though:
我们本来有一支精锐队伍
We did have one unit doing high-end stuff--
大力制止了Clinton街的重大案件
Major Crimes working out of  an offsite down on Clinton Street.
"本来"是过去式 怎么解散了?
"Did" is past tense. What wrecked it?
问得好 市长先生
Good question,Mr. Mayor.
Ray Foersters去世以后
With Ray Foersters'passing,
我马上需要一名新的警察局总指挥官
I'm going to need a new ClD commander right away.
你肯不肯在Rawls手下做个副总警监?
Would you object to being made colonel working under Rawls?
Rawls手下?
Under Rawls?
他不是安全局副局长么
He is deputy ops, is he not:
市长是真想做出改变
Is the mayor going to make the changes
还是把活留给好战士?
or just leave it to the good soldier?
我想问的是 您到底有多认真
What I'm really asking is: How for real are you?
这个嘛 看来我们要一起发现了 不是吗
Well, I guess we're going to find that out together, aren't we...
Daniels副总警监
Colonel Daniels?
我们该他妈怎么办?
What the fuck do we do?
不知道 这帮家伙根本不怕
I don't know. These guys don't scare.
如果大家一起凑钱 你 我 Sydnor
If we all kick in-- you, me, Sydnor--
说不定能买台二手摄像机
maybe we could afford a used camera.
我想过了
I thought of that.
序列号跟我LSD的不一样
It ain't gonna match the serial  numbers from the one for my lSD.
我们只能对Marlo来硬的
We've gotta get wood on Marlo.
没别的办法
It's the only way.
这个叫Randy的小子 他说不出谋杀对吧
This Randy kid, he can't give us a murder, right?
连尸体都说不出个所以然来
Shit, he can't even give us a body.
可他说那个叫小Kevin的
But he says some Little Kevin kid
本该是他叫Lex到巷子里去
was the one supposed to tell Lex to go up in that alley.
还有 丫说小Kevin说了什么?
Plus, what did fuck-nut say Little Kev said?
"Lex到巷子里去了
"Lex went up the alley,
不过他不会回来了"
but he ain't coming back."
也许他目睹了整件事
Maybe he saw the whole thing.
也许他才是目击证人
Maybe he's our eyeball witness.
- 小Kevin - 小Kevin
- Little Kevin: - Little Kevin.
这儿四叠
Carry the four.
80 100 10 20
80, 100, 10, 20.
剩下的呢
Where's the rest?
嗯 我遇到点麻烦
Um... I'm on a hard strip.
Lafayette那儿不好办
It's tricky on Lafayette.
你他妈去那边干嘛了
What the fuck are you doing there?
我得慢慢上手嘛
I've got to build it up.
我呸 慢慢上手个屁
Nah nah, you ain't got to build up shit.
你爹让他们当了街角小子
Your father built them corners,
他们都欠你的 因为他们都欠你爹
and they owe you 'cause they owe him.
该还账的时候Bodie的记性就不够用了
Bodie's got a real short memory when it comes to giving props.
妈
Ma.
我现在就去把这事儿弄明白
I going to straighten this shit out right now.
妈 让我慢慢来嘛
Ma, let me build.
妈
Ma!
长官
Sir.
Bill
Bill...
我们要重组一下
we need to regroup.
我为新管理层想了点新点子
I've come up with something fresh for the new administration.
呐 我不介意告诉你
Hmm? I don't mind telling you,
我看不惯Carcetti在咱的地盘上转来转去
I'm uncomfortable with the way Carcetti is running around in our shop.
- 他提起过我? - 提到几次
-He's talked to me?? -several times.
你也在打小算盘是吧?
You're making your move, huh?
我们曾经是好战友 你和我
We were a good team,you and me.
曾经是 没错
We were.
- Ella小姐 Bug人呢? - 他回家了 Michael
- Miss Ella, where Bug at? - He went home, Michael.
不 他说好等我的
Nah, he waits for me.
有个男的来接他走了 说是他爹
The man who came and picked him up said he was his father.
Bug也承认的
And Bug said so, too.
操
Fuck!
你他妈干了什么
What the fuck did you do?
你干嘛由着他干?
And why'd you let him do it?
- 听我说  - 不
- Hey, listen to me-- - No.
你就这么让他头脑发热
That's how you got him with his head up his ass--
结了的命案都能推翻
unsolving his own fucking murders.
你的工作是把红的字变成黑的  不是反过来
Your job is to turn red to black, not the other way.
你 别让他牵着鼻子走
And you, stand the fuck up for yourself.
不能都掰着指头算啊 小子
You don't got to do the whole thing  on your fingers,little man.
来 先算
Look, first count--
六加六等于...
six and six is...
先写下2 十位数加到这边
Put down the two, you bring over the one.
- Bug - 嗨 小伙子
- Bug. - Hey, big man.
到我这边来
Get over to me now.
- 我们正在做... - 过来
- We were just going to-- - Now.
喂  等下
Yo, hold on.
喂 那个值800块钱呢 你欠我!
Yo, you owe me $800 on that, bitch. You owe!